Hello. Uh, it is fantastic to be at the
grill. Thanks to Sharon and the entire
team at the RAP for having us. I'm Brent
Weinstein. I am part of the senior
leadership team at CIA where I oversee
our digital media work. And before we
jump in, I want to address uh a I guess
elephant in the room that Darmman is not
on stage. Uh, his wife uh they're having
a baby and it came a little quicker than
we thought. First of all, happy for Dar.
Uh, I'm thrilled to be here. I'm
thrilled to be here with Shawn, which
was always part of the plan, and Tony,
who so graciously stepped in uh at the
last minute. And I'm going to ask them
just to briefly introduce themselves,
then we'll get into the conversation. So
Sean, why don't we start with you?
>> Uh I'm now an uncle. Um the um uh my
name is Sean Atkins. I'm CEO of Darmman.
I've been there for about a year.
Previous to Darmman, uh I've worked at
every major media company except for
Comcast NBC. Um, so, um, I'll have a lot
of war stories I'm sure we'll talk about
over the course of the panel.
>> Fantastic. And Tony, thank you for being
here. Why don't you briefly give us a
quick intro?
>> Hi, I'm Tony Gray. I'm head of
production at Darmman Studios. I've been
there about seven months now. I come
from Linear Television, Fremantle, MGM,
Prior.
>> So, thank you for being here. And as
we're going to talk about today, uh, the
way that Darmman Studios manages
production is unlike anything most of
you, most of us have ever seen. and and
Tony's a big part of that. So, thank you
for joining us. Um Sean, as you've
mentioned, you've worked for a lot of
media companies. Most of them were
fairly traditional. Uh and then, you
know, you and I together many years ago.
Uh you started migrating towards digital
media. And you know, let's talk about
that migration and in particular, what
made you excited to make the leap to a
creator centric company like Darmman
Studios? Yeah, like I always tell people
if you um cover the names on my resume,
what you'll see is I clearly am
attracted to new growth where the
opportunity is. And so uh I've always
sort of acted as if I was the audience.
So my career was like I went into cable
when all my classmates at USC film
school went into one of the theatrical
films because I didn't have any
contacts. It was the only thing I could
break into. And then I went into the
internet when everybody else is like
that's never going to be anything. So I
always sort of went to where the
audience went. So it wasn't a surprise
that sort of as creators were coming up
that I sort of thought that was the next
thing to do. In particularly what
attracted me to DAR is for those of you
who've ever had a chance to see his
facilities. It's like it's a little bit
shocking. You sort of think that's
what's happening in the industry and
then you see what DAR has done. That was
my first aha moment. The second aha
moment is if you follow Dar's story,
it's not the story of somebody who grew
up every day being like I want to be a
creative. It's actually a story of
somebody who went through like every
failure or challenge one could go
through in their life. religious
persecution, racial persecution, abusive
relationships, you know, going bankrupt,
getting in trouble of the law. Like I
told it was like from a story structure,
it's like everything you could put your
hero through, he went through. And as he
sort of got to this low point in his
life in his 30s, he realized that uh his
way out through depression and all those
sort of challenges was that he listened
to stories about other people being
successful and that he started to
realize that you know the story that the
great human universal story is that it
almost failure is almost a prerequisite
for success and that inspired him to
just start talking a camera and lo and
behold that begat what became Darmman
Studios and so the chance to be part of
a storyteller whose story is so
organically who they are and what they
want to put into the world, put good
content and the fact it's obviously so
resonant is a really hard thing to say
no to when you're sort of standing there
having that conversation with someone
like D.
>> That's amazing. And you know Tony
similarly you got your start at
Fremantle and a number of you know
really traditional production companies
and here you are working for arguably
the biggest and certainly most
voluminous in terms of output uh digital
content studio in the world. How did
you, you know, find yourself making that
migration?
>> It was really interesting. So, like I
posted a LinkedIn um post a little bit
ago. Like when I decided to jump out of
linear television, it was really tough
because like that defined me for so many
years of my life and it was so different
that Hollywood frowned upon jumping into
that world into this world. And I have
to tell you that it is a totally
different life. It is an incredible
culture. It's collaborative. We
basically tell stories at the water
cooler. We can make those stories. We
can ideulate and deliver in 30 days. So
I come in and speak to the showrunner
about something that happened to me on a
weekend. He writes it and the show goes
viral. It's it's amazing to see
something happen that fast. You have no
network notes. You have no downtime. You
know, it doesn't have to be green lit.
We just come back and do it.
>> That's amazing. Um, for people in the
audience who maybe aren't as familiar
with Darmman, Sean, the numbers are just
staggering subscribers and and and
annual views and uh the engagement, you
know, maybe talk about some of those
highlights so people can get a sense of
the scale.
>> Yeah. So to put it in in context, uh
when Dar started, he was just talking to
camera about a year into his first, this
is in 19 in 2018, uh 2018, uh about the
end of the year, he saw he's writing a
story on a napkin, which today we will
retroactively call a script. Uh and he
saw two people in his apartment sort of
doing the thing he was writing about. He
looked up and he's like, "Hold this
moment. Can you mind?" By it was his
brother-in-law and his wife's best
friend. Do you mind sort of just doing
this while I shoot it? That was the very
first scripted thing that Dar did that
went to a million views in 2018. The
very next scripted, well, it actually
was a script in all intention video he
made 250 million views. So within his
first year, by the end of 2019, he was
the number one video streamed creator on
all of Facebook. By 2020, he was the
number two behind Jimmy on uh YouTube.
Put that into actual hard metrics. The
thing you have to understand about DAR
is we actually make 16 by9 halfhour
television episodes. We do about five
half five hours of television volume a
week and it's about a 1.2 billion long
form streams per month. If you look at
on a daily basis, his content does
somewhere around 45 million streams uh
just for on the library alone, which
would make that any day of the week his
streams would have outperformed the
finale of Game of Thrones by three
times.
>> Correct? So you give you sort of the
context of the volume. If you just
actually if I wanted to play against
Neielson I was like okay I'll take all
the views just do US just do prime time
just do 18 to 49. He'd be the largest
scripted television show on US linear
television every single night to give
you a sense of scale.
>> Five nights a week.
>> Five nights a week
>> Tony. Yeah that's incredible. Somehow
all that content has to get made. 30
minutes a day. Five days a week. 30 day
production cycles from an idea to it,
you know, being on the internet.
>> How do you do that?
>> Nobody sleeps.
>> Exactly.
>> No, actually, we have an incredible
culture at the company, which I love so
much. Um, we have about eight crews.
We'll be ramping up to nine by the end
of the year. Um, we run simultaneously
all the time. We have three different
studios. I'm sure you know you mentioned
we have about a 125,000 square ft of
space. We have about 90 different sets
um and we just turn out crews non-stop.
>> I think one of the things to understand
is that to get that level of efficiency
you have to sort of think different and
I think one of the things that makes Dar
interesting I was attracted to coming to
work for him was because he did not come
from traditional media and this is
actually true of entrepreneurs in a lot
of different businesses. the
entrepreneurs who have a tendency to
break the format or break the model is
because they don't come from the
industry. So, they don't know all the
rules. So, in Dar's case, when he wrote
his first like half hour television
show,
>> he didn't know that you needed like 200
crew. He's like, I need a camera and a
script. That was literally it. And so,
when you come into the studio, to Tony's
point, like a lot of what Tony's put in
place is like unbelievable efficiency,
right? So you have a lot of
specialization that happens a lot of um
things for example we built a completely
bespoke software system that when a
script is written it is ingested into
the software system immediately broken
into all the component parts shot to the
different departments. So if you're
sitting in wardrobe you get a checklist
that says of these nine productions
going on today the following outfits for
this actor or actress need to be in this
location at this period of time done.
Right? So there's no people involved.
It's literally just software that
delivers that. And at the same time, the
same thing happens at the end of the
day. And so out of that, you get this
unbelievable efficiency where they'll
produce a TV episode for approximately
1/100th the cost of a linear average
episode.
>> It's amazing. I I think when many people
think of internet content or social
media content, they think of creators in
their bedroom or in their garage or
running around the streets, you know,
filming prank videos with an iPhone. Uh
what you do is more like operating a
backlot. Uh, I joke, although I'm not
sure I'm all that far off, that the
facade frontage that you have in your
studio is probably equivalent to that of
most back lots at a major studio. And
and what's astounding to me is how
thoughtful you use space. Uh, if you go
down one hallway and film it from one
perspective, it's a cl it's like a high
school, but when you go in the other
direction, it's an apartment building.
You have classrooms that can be turned
into movie theaters. I mean it it's
really amazing how malleable uh the
space is. Can you talk a little bit
about how that evolved because now
you're in three warehouses in Burbank.
Uh and it's like nothing any of us have
ever seen in this particular sector.
>> Yeah. What's sort of funny is and it's
um is it sort of started on accident,
right? Because Dar and Laura who founded
the company were shooting it in their in
their apartment and then COVID hit. So
you couldn't get space anywhere else as
they were growing. So they rented a
location. It was too big for the
businesses that they were running at the
time, which they ran two beauty
businesses and they were starting a
Darmman Studios. And so, uh, they rented
this large space and they were just
going to use a part of it and sublet it.
And they had enough money to build one
set. So, they built the first set, which
is a small little apartment. When you
walk in, when we do the tour, we walk
you into it first. Like, this is where
it started. And then they had enough
money and they built a second set. And
then enough money and they built a
school set. And so, when you come into
DM1, it's actually a little bit um,
scattershot, right? to your point where
you'll see today um when I was doing a
tour, someone's walking to I'm like,
"Oh, this is a hospital." And then we
turn the corner and they look at it,
they're like, "It actually looks like
the governor's office." I'm like, "Today
it's a governor's office, but it was
built to be a hospital. Um it also plays
at a school. It plays like So part of it
was because you have to think at
different economics." The other thing
that's to your point about space is if
you go through the studios, you'll
notice because we do multi-quadrant,
multigenerational
um uh content that everything you need
to shoot an episode is actually
self-contained in one of the lots,
right? If you need a school, places to
work, retail establishments, they're all
in one location. So that comes from the
data analysis because we look at the
crew space every single like quarter and
then we'll reoptimize the sets based on
efficiencies of production. We're like,
"Oh, it turns out that we stopped down
too many times because we've been using
this one beauty salon and it's causing
us a problem in capacity. We'll build
another one in another set to sort of
open that up. So it's always about using
data to analyze the efficiency to make
sure that we can kind of keep that cost
efficiency down for for the kind of
digital economics." you know, Tony, when
when you're, you know, managing the
output that Darmman is responsible for,
when you start doing the math, you know,
you know, billions of of of views times
30 minutes per video, you start to get
the watch time that is, you know, as big
or bigger as anything in traditional
media. How do you keep it fresh? How do
you make sure that when you're on your
400th video of the year that you're
like, "Oh, wait, wait, wait. You know,
we're not you. Let's make sure we don't
use the exact same set in the exact same
sequence that we used, you know, in
another video. How do you keep it all
straight?
>> It's definitely a puzzle, but it's the
collaboration of the entire team. Like,
they're incredible. So, we'll talk
amongst ourselves and we have pre-pros
and we'll even change things in pre-pro
and we because we have such an
incredible team. If we do feel like
something has just been seen, they'll be
changing it while we're doing the table
read at the same time. So, and everybody
comes in with ideas all the time. And
like I said, we take the real life ideas
that happened in the week with everyone
and we just have such this collaborative
team that we'll say what happened on the
weekend. We had went to a party and then
we write it and it goes into scripting
the following day.
>> And how big's the team? How many people
work at Darmman Studios?
>> We have about 200 people.
>> It's amazing. All full-time employees.
>> That's incredible. Um, you know, Sean,
I've always been blown away by many
stories that come out of what happens at
at Darmman. The Christmas, you know, uh,
special was was one that I think is
particularly entertaining. I think the
audience would love to hear it.
>> So, for those of us who've been in, uh,
traditional media and know the the the
loving phrase development hell, which is
like, you know, um, spend your time
behind trying to make a story work or
break a story and you could spend a
year, two years making something happen.
Uh, true story. We're going to be doing
the very first um Christmas movie, full
90 90-minute length movie for DAR uh
studios this year. And it literally
happened in one day. So, in the morning,
uh, me and Dar were sitting around with
Reuben, who's our showrunner. We're
like, "Hey, we think we want to do a we
should probably do a Christmas movie."
By the by lunchtime, we're like, "That's
a pretty good idea." We started throwing
log lines around. By the afternoon, we
uh were talking to Tony about like,
"What do you have the production
capacity for it? when do we need to get
started? And by that evening, we
actually had written out the treatment
and sent it off to a writer. And so that
actually was uh 24 hours from idea to
actually going into writing and it's
going into production in about a week.
So it's going to be our very first
movie. And and I would tell you having
done those before in my previous career,
that would have been a conversation that
took me about a year.
>> That's amazing. And it is it going to be
released on Christmas or
>> uh we're well it's
>> we might move it because we're doing
we're not just doing a movie we're doing
the 12 days of Christmas and based on a
couple conversations we're having with
brand partners the dates might have to
move. So is latest premiere be Christmas
Eve?
>> Uh you mentioned brand partners and I'll
stick with you for a moment. Uh you have
these amazing facades. You know they're
generic. It's a generic movie theater a
generic uh you know uh perfume store. a
generic shoe store in the mall. Uh it
seems like there's lots of opportunities
to work with brands and frankly lots of
partners. So, you know, as you think of
and who knows who's in the audience
today, as you think of uh the types of
partners that you're excited to work
with, uh is there any in particular that
uh that that come to mind as we think
about what you're capable of there and
the type of people who might be here?
>> Yeah, I think the first thing, you know,
we we care about the mission of the
company, right? The mission of the
company is to put good into the world.
Um, you know, if you talk to Dar and
Laura, very r very, not that they're not
savvy business people. They're very
rarely being like, what's the dollar
we're going to make on it? It's very
much like, is this on the mission to put
good content in the world that families
feel comfortable with that we think is
making the world a better place? They're
teaching sort of values in the kind of
universal human sense uh through
storytelling. And so that's question
one. So we look for that in partners,
right? So I sort of say to people when
they ask me like we're definitely not
going to be working with Smith and
Wesson anytime soon, right? Not not not
that that that that's a judgment I'm
making, but it doesn't align with sort
of the values of the company. The second
thing that we think about is the
long-term nature of it because as a
creator you live and die on the
relationship with the creator and it's
so immediate and so connected and so
real. You have to be authentic. And
because we do scripted content and in
the scale that we do it at, it's pretty
authentic if a brand came to me and
said, "Hey, can you turn the the uh
coffee shop in there to a Starbucks for
one episode and then I have to switch it
back to something else. It just doesn't
feel real." The inverse of that for the
brands we work well with is that they
understand we're emotional storytellers.
If you're a brand, what do you want to
be associated with? Just pure spectacle
or you want to be associated with kind
of deep emotional connection, which is
what we do. And then our number one
comment uh from our fans in the in the
comment list on any analysis says the
word crying. Uh it gives a sense of sort
of what we do. Um and so the brands that
we're having conversations with are
really about almost like I would say
it's almost like Dar as chief creator
officer. It's really a long-term
relationship where they're going to be
one of a very small subset of people.
They're going to be deeply embedded to
many of the facades, many of the story
lines. A story I I used as an example
with one brand the other day. Okay, they
were like, "Give me an example of like
how you're different." I said, "Well,
you could have Dar in the middle of the
thing, like in the middle of emotional
scene and be like, buy Avon, right?"
Which is the typical creator way to do
it. Or the example we did for a big
gaming company. It was like we did a
episode about a half hour show about a
about a young teen whose dream was to be
a streamer and that people didn't
believe in the dream and so they had to
kind of kind of accomplish it on their
own. So, traditional heroes arc. What do
you think the 72 shots of video game
footage were about in that hero's
journey without us ever saying a thing?
It was this one product and it went from
like 27 in the app store to number two
instantaneously without sort of like a
because it was a very organic real way
to bring a product into the brand and
that's sort of the direction that we're
going in and the the CMOs who really
want to get in bed with us are having
those sort of conversations with us.
what uh
you're known as being a a a studio that
primarily distributes on social
platforms like YouTube and and Facebook,
but you're expanding. Uh most recently,
uh there was a deal where uh you not
only created a fast channel with Samsung
TV Plus, but I think you might have been
the first partner of Samsung to actually
have original content baked into that
type. Can you talk a little bit about
that? Yeah. So I mean look the our we
are born of social and that's our first
love and but doesn't mean that we don't
want our content to move anywhere. I
always tell people like wherever DAR has
moved his content it's been successful.
I one I like to make a joke about is we
put our content for example on Spotify
right scripted dramas. We're a top 100
podcaster. It's not a podcast right? So
because it's these universal themes that
work globally. And so Samsung saw that
they saw our production capability. So
they came as a very different
perspective. It wasn't like we'll
license your library and then we'll do
everything. It was more like what do you
want to do? How do you want to reach the
audience? How can you use user
resources? Because by the way making
television shows for fast at the
traditional model is expensive. And so
that was interesting an interesting way.
So the way we have a tendency to have
the conversations with partners is
they're trying to figure out how to
reach the audiences on their platform,
what they care about, and then they want
to have a conversation with us when it's
successful about how do we use our
audience reach and our infrastructure to
think about a different model to help
achieve what they want without going
through the traditional long production
uh cycles, without going through the
traditional long development cycles. cuz
we could go to like an SVOD player and
for the same cost of a traditional
thing, give them probably 10 times the
volume at a similar quality, which would
allow them to almost act like YouTube.
That one worked, that one didn't, that
one worked, that one didn't. And our
turnaround time, because as Tony said,
is like 30 days. If you renewed
something, you don't wait 18 months, you
wait like 30 days.
>> There's a uh uh what is hopefully a
sustained uh revival in people going to
the movie theaters. Uh and there's some
fantastic data that uh Eduardo Akuna,
who's the CEO of Regal, who was here
earlier, has shared uh about how one of
the biggest cohorts that are going to
the theaters are uh people that were
born after 2010 and they're going there
to escape their digital lives and
they're going there to have a communal
experience and that seems to be right in
line with your demographic. Do you ever
see Darmman uh making content for
theaters or
>> It's funny, I think it'd be the And I
actually told him this last night. I
said it's sort of uh the perfect
partnership because obviously we have a
huge cohort of that generation. Uh the
second thing is if you think about it um
probably the number one thing that DAR
the company gets asked by fans is can I
be in a Darmman episode because it's so
universal in its themes. It's so
relatable and the audience really feels
a sense of ownership to so they feel
like it's accessible to them. The second
thing we get asked the most is can you
tell my story? Because every human
being, everyone in here, if I spend
enough time with you, has some
fascinating story of where you're being
persecuted or challenged or not being
able to live up to the ideals that you
want to and then you came through that
on the other side of learning, which is
sort of what our value proposition is.
And so we think actually the opportunity
is to kind of sort of do a bit of a
national tour with all that facility
space that they have and have people
come in, tell their stories, put them on
social and then allow the community in
those local towns to sort of choose the
story they want for us to make and
premiere in that in that DMA.
>> That's an amazing also put it on our
socials which would be a real way to
sort of use that facility and have a
reason to go to the theater on top of
the experience you get watching movies
which I love but also another experience
to draw them in there for that exper
that community experience. So, uh,
before we wrap up, because our our time
was winding down, you know, to you,
Tony, uh, you told me an amazing
anecdote about when your Tesla died and
and how that, uh, exemplified
>> uh, what's possible at a company as
dynamic and nimble and innovative as
Darmman Studios, I think it'd be a great
story to end with.
>> I
was at a summit much like this one. My
phone died. I was like, it's fine. I'm
amongst friends. It was late. I walked
out to my car and was like, I can't get
in my car because I only have my phone
with me. So, being the production person
that I am, I had my computer so that I
could use my computer to charge my phone
to get into my car. But I went back the
next day and I told my showrunner the
story of like, I'm the blonde girl left
in the parking lot, can't get in my car,
and then he wrote a story line about it
and it went viral. So, it happened that
fast, that quick. And that's what I said
like we create stories every day in our
lives that everybody can relate to. And
when I tell that story to other people,
I can't even tell you like five people
already that I have already told that
story to, the same exact thing happened
to them. So they're watching these
videos and they become a part of the
actual video itself because they too
have that story that we can relate to
and then we can tell the rest of the
world. So once again, uh, thank you to
Sharon Waxman. Thank you to everyone at
the RAP. Congratulations to Darmman and
his expanding family. Thank you so much
to Sean, who we anticipated being here,
and to Tony, who literally raced here
when we called her 90 minutes ago. Uh,
and thanks to all of you for being a
great Thanks for having us. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
[Applause]